# Oleksandr Kreshchuk

Highly motivated Ukrainian UI designer. Able to create visually appealing digital products, including websites, applications, and graphic elements with animation in 3D. Proven experience working in visual design supporting multiple companies and designers for 3 years. Currently looking for a design job or internship remotely or in Rhode Island.

(401) 648-5449 oleksandr.kre@gmail.com olkre.github.io

East Providence, RI 02914

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Wood & Room, Visual Designer

JAN 2020 - MAY 2023; Kyiv

Responsible for creating a website design, logo, and other graphic materials. Creating 3D visualizations for new furniture models and developing instructions for their assembling.

# **Bright Gift**, Visual Designer

FEB 2021 - OCT 2022; Irpin, Kyiv;

Working with other designers and the production team designing various graphic materials, such as cards, banners, and 2D designs for wooden decorations. Producing 3D representations of decor models.

# Nazar Kulikov Agency, Junior UI/Web designer

MAY 2022 - AUG 2022, Remote

Designing interfaces, web and mobile apps in different fields. Created website designs from scratch by collecting references, wireframing, and iterating processes. Worked on and improved existing interfaces using guidelines and atomic design. Made custom 3d illustrations for products.

#### **FREELANCE PROJECTS**

## **Svoim-po-viri** — *March* 2022

Collaborated with another designer on a volunteer project that designed a website to assist Ukrainian refugees in finding help in foreign countries. Created wireframes, desktop, and mobile versions in Figma.

### **SP-EL** — *June* 2021

Redesigned a full e-commerce website for the supplier of electronic components in Figma. Created refreshed UI, structured and made information presentation more compact. Modeled and rendered higher-quality pictures for products.

## WorkPlace — April 2021

MVP web app design for a start-up that promotes cafes and coworking places for freelancers. Created user flow, and designed desktop and mobile versions in Figma. Also organized a developer guide with styles and fonts.

#### **EDUCATION**

**School №185,** Kyiv — Ukrainian High-School

SEP 2019 - MAY 2022

## **GBCA**, **Attleboro** — Foundations of Computer Programming

SEP 2023 - MAY 2023

High school elective class, Python and HTML, CSS basics

## **MBU**, Online — College Algebra Class

JAN 2023 - MAY 2023

#### **LANGUAGES**

Native: Ukrainian

Fluent: English, Russian

#### **SKILLS**

UI/UX/Web design: atomic structure, HIG, user flow, wireframing, prototyping

Polygonal 3D: modeling, rigging, animation, compositing, rendering, character design

**Graphic Design:** composition, work with brand style, simple illustration

Animation: UI interaction, simple 2d animation

#### **TOOLS**

**Figma** (including components, styles)

Blender

Adobe:

After Effects, Photoshop, Premiere, Illustrator

**Marvelous Designer** 

Framer (Beginner)

HTML, CSS, and
Bootstrap understanding
and basics